createandcraft.com 2017-06-27

# Privacy Policy | Create and Craft

At Create and Craft, we want you to know how we collect and use information about you when you use the www.createandcraft.com website, place an order by telephone (including through our interactive voice response service) , use our mobile applications or otherwise provide us with information by email or other means (the “ C&C Services”). This Privacy Policy describes information that can identify you (“personal information”) that we collect, what we use your personal information for, when we might disclose that information, and how you can manage use of that information. By using the www.createandcraft.com website (the “Site”) or the C&C Services, you are accepting the practices described in this policy. 

### Information We May Collect

We collect information that can identify you when you register with the Site, or place an order with us by use of the C&C Services. This includes your name, postal address, email address, telephone number and credit card information. We may also collect information that does not personally identify you, such as your IP address and information about your location and use of the Site and the Internet. We may supplement the information that you provide to us with information we receive from third parties. 

### Use of Your Personal Information

We may use information that you provide or that is obtained by us in the following ways:

•Provide you with the content, products and services you request.  
•Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us and send you information about features and enhancements on or to our Site or to the C&C Services.  
•Communicate with you about changes to our policies.  
•Personalize content and experiences on our Site, including providing you recommendations based on your preferences.  
•Send you newsletters, offers and promotions for our products and services, third party products and services, or special events by e-mail, text, or other another medium.  
•Provide you with advertising, including advertising based on your activity on our Site or activity on third party sites and applications.  
•Administer contests, sweepstakes, promotions, and surveys.  
•Carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection.  
•Optimize or improve our products, services and operations.  
•Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal.  
•Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Site and the C&C Services and their purchasing patterns.  
•In any other way we may describe when you provide the information  
•For any other purpose with your consent.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link or who may link to us. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies of third party websites. 

### Disclosure of Your Information

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this Privacy Policy:

•To employees and agents of Craft Retail International Limited (“Craft”), which operates the Create and Craft television channel, the Site and the C&C Services, and to Craft’s parent company and other corporate affiliates.   
•To contractors, service providers, agents, and other third parties we use to support our business, including credit card payment processors and product suppliers.  
•To sponsors, advertisers and other third parties to market their products or services to you unless you have asked not to receive such information. We require these third parties to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them.  
• To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it.   
•To anyone to whom we transfer or may transfer our rights and duties under our agreement with you;  
•To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other sale or transfer of some or all of Craft's assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by Craft about the users of our Services is among the assets transferred.  
•For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.

We may also disclose your personal information:

•To comply with any court order, law or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request.  
•To enforce or apply our [Terms and Conditions](http://www.createandcraft.com/us/terms-and-conditions-use.aspx "Terms and Conditions") of Use and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes.  
•If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of Craft, our customers or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

We may disclose or share information that is not personal information in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary. Among other things, we will disclose non-personally identifiable information to third parties to help us determine how people use parts of the Site and who our users are so we can improve our Site and the C&C Services. We will also disclose non-personally identifiable information to our partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use the Site. 

### Security

We are concerned about ensuring the security of your personal information. We endeavor to take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information. However, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you provide to us. You accept the inherent security risks of providing information and making purchases over the Internet and we cannot be held responsible for any breach of security that is not willful or negligent. All of your personal data, including credit card information is encrypted using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) Technology. 

### Your Choices About Use of Personal Information

**Changing Your Registration Information**   
To change any of your registered details on the Site, click on 'your account' and enter your login name and password. Once logged in, change any of the details shown and click 'change details'. 

**Opting Out of Promotional Offers from Create and Craft**  
You may always opt-out of receiving future e-mail marketing messages and newsletters from us. We provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us by logging into your account and adjusting your communications settings. If you receive a promotional e-mail from us and you wish to opt out in the future, you may click the “Unsubscribe” link. If you receive a promotional text message and wish to opt out in the future, please reply to the message with “STOP.” You may also opt out by logging in to your account and changing your Marketing Preferences. You may not opt-out of receiving transactional e-mails related to your account with us. 

### No Children Under the Age of 13

The Site and the C&C Services are not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not sell products for purchase by children and products we sell must be purchased by adults. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on this Site or through the C&C Services. 

### California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident you have the right to request certain information regarding our disclosure of your personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To obtain this information, please send an email message to [customer.service@createandcraft.com](mailto:customer.service@createandcraft.com) with “Request for California Privacy Information” in the subject line of your message. Please allow thirty days for a response. 

Currently, our Site does not recognize automated browser signals regarding “do not track” instructions. If we develop this capability in the future, we will update this Privacy Policy to describe how we respond to such signals. 

### Cookies

Like many websites, we use “cookies”, which are small text files that are stored on your computer or equipment that record your preferences and actions. We use cookies to track use of our Site and online services. We may also use cookies to monitor traffic, improve the Site and make it easier and/or relevant for your use.

There are two types of cookies: session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie expires shortly after you close your browser. Persistent cookies are stored on your hard drive until they expire or are deleted. Both types of cookies are used to make it easier for you to navigate our Website -- for example, by remembering your shopping preferences, shopping cart, and user information.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but, if you prefer, you can usually modify your browser setting to disable or reject cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this Site may then be inaccessible or not function properly. For more information on cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information provided by the Interactive Advertising Bureau at [www.allaboutcookies.org.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

We may also use web beacons or flash cookies. A web beacon or flash cookie (also known as “action tags”, “tracer tags”, or “single-pixel gifs”) is an invisible graphic on a web page that is programmed to collect non-personally identifiable information about your use of a given website. We do not share or provide personally identifiable information we may collect through such web beacons, such as names, e-mail addresses and phone numbers, without your express permission. 

We may partner with third party advertising companies who may utilize flash or enhanced cookies or web beacons to better provide advertisements about our products and services that may be of interest to you. These third parties may use cookies alone or in conjunction with web beacons or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use the Site. They may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based advertising or other targeted content. These partners do not have access to or use your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number or other personally identifiable information from us, without your consent. They may, however, use persistent identifiers to anonymously track your internet usage across other websites in their networks beyond this Site. Such third parties may, with sufficient data from other sources, be able to personally identify you, unknown to us. We do not control these third parties' tracking technologies or how they may be used. If you have any questions about an advertisement or other targeted content, you should contact the responsible provider directly. 

### Changes to this Policy

We may update the Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes in our Services and practices. We will post changes to the Privacy Policy on the Site so that you will know about changes in the way we gather, use or share your personal information. We may also notify you of material changes in the Privacy Policy by sending an email, but you should check this Privacy Policy each time you use the Site in case you missed a notice of changes. Your continued use of our Site after we make changes will mean you accept those changes in our policy and practices. 

### How to Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you should contact us by email at [customer.services@createandcraft.com](mailto:customer.services@createandcraft.com) with “PRIVACY POLICY” in the subject line.

Last updated: December 4th 2014
